Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we
have a very descriptive lesson for you.
That's right, we have
an elementary lesson for
everyone and we are going
to talk about facial hair.
Okay, so Marco you
don't have any facial hair?
I don't. Well, I like to shave every other
day but yeah, that's what facial hair is.
This is hair that you have on your face.
Okay, so we're at the
police station in this dialogue.
Let's take a listen
and find out why.
Okay Sally, we have
an artist here to help us.
We'll ask you questions
about the bank robber you
saw and Paul will draw
a picture. Are you ready?
Yes, well he had brown hair, long hair and
he had some facial hair. It was brown too.
Good, okay the facial hair
was it a beard or a mustache?
Both. His mustache was very short
and thin just on the top of his lip.
Uh huh, hmm like this?
Yes, that's the mustache
but the beard isn't right.
I mean it didn't
cover his whole face.
I think it was just on his chin.
A goat team? Was it like Paul's?
Uh yes, that's it. He had a goat team.
Okay, now what about sideburns?
Did he have sideburns?
Yes, they were long and thick, like yours.
All right, there was this the man you saw.
Yes, that's him. It looks a lot like you.
Hmm, why yes he does.
Paul, where were you on Friday afternoon?
What? That's ridiculous.
He wasn't me. I didn't do anything.
I was over there doing the thing
with the best man, who to do.
All right, we're back. So as you can see
the woman is describing a bank robber
and one of the ways that she's describing
him is by the facial hair that he had.
So there are a lot of very
interesting words and phrases here.
Why don't we take a look at
some of them in language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
Okay, so in language
takeaway today we have
some really good description words and
nouns, things that people have on their face.
Facial hair, because there's
not just one kind of facial
hair, there are
many different kinds.
So our first one is, are we
going to skip facial hair?
Yeah, we're going to skip.
Okay, our first one is mustache.
Okay, a mustache. And this is, I think, one
of the more popular forms of facial hair.
I think it's a style, right?
All these styles of facial hair.
That's right. And so a mustache is
basically some hair on top of your lip.
It's above your lip.
And it's usually, it can
be thin or thick. It
comes in different sizes,
but this is not your whole face.
It's just above your lip.
All right, so for example,
a famous person or
a famous mustache was
Charlie Chaplin, right?
That's right. Charlie
Chaplin had a mustache,
just a little bit of
hair above his lip,
but also Theodore Roosevelt had a
very big bushy mustache. That's right.
Interesting fact, you might hear
someone say stash instead of mustache.
This is a short way to say it.
So, oh, he's growing a stash.
Right. And also the
spelling can be a little bit
difficult to understand
how you pronounce it,
because it's M-U-S-T-A-C-H-E.
So, there's no really S-H sound like sh.
But you pronounce it mustache. Mustache.
Yeah. So, that's one kind of facial hair,
but there are many
others. The next one we've
got for you is a beard.
A beard. Okay. This is a
really good one. A beard. I
think a beard keeps men warm.
I think a beard keeps a
man warm in the winter.
Yeah, definitely.
This is the most hair.
So, basically, a beard
you have hair on your lip,
and also all over your face, basically.
So, a beard, you have all over your face.
Right. Your cheeks, your
chin, and above your lip.
Okay. Very good. So, a
famous person with a beard,
Santa Claus. Santa Claus
has a very big beard. Yeah.
Santa Claus has a bigger
beard. Big white beard.
Okay. So, that's a
beard. I think that's the
easiest to have, because
you don't need to cut
anything or shave anything.
Oh, you need to, you need to.
Yeah, you need
to. If you don't trim,
it looks kind of bad. Right. Well, now,
moving on to our next style of facial hair,
we have a go-tee. Okay.
This might be confusing
for some people,
because it's not a beard,
and it's not a mustache. It's
basically hair around your mouth.
Right. On your
chin and your lip.
So, I think for Sean Connery,
it has a very famous go-tee.
And Brad Pitt right now
has a really big go-tee.
Okay. A long
go-tee. Lots of hair.
So, as you say, it's
around your mouth.
So, your lip and your
chin. That's right. A go-tee.
Okay. So, that's our
third style of facial hair,
and now moving on to our
last style, we have sideburns.
Okay. So, think about the word here,
sideburns, side. They're on your side.
They're on the side. So,
near the ears, there is usually
some space where a
man can grow some hair.
Not with a beard or
necessarily mustache, though.
It can be just the hair
on the jawline, near the
jaw, near the ears. Okay.
So, I think this was a very
famous style in the '60s
and '70s. You would let
you would have long
sideburns all along your face.
That's right. Past
your ear. Right.
That's right. And the longer,
maybe the sexier you were.
The sexier. No, but
these days it's not as
popular, but you do see
people who have sideburns.
I think nowadays people have
sideburns, but they're not as thick.
They're just thin
little sideburns.
Yeah, that's right. All
right. So, all of these
are the different sorts
and styles of facial hair.
Of course, there are a
lot more. I think while
we were looking for
this on the internet,
we found a lot of other
styles that came up like
mutton chops and things
like this, but these are
probably the most
popular ones. That's right.
These are the ones you're
going to hear about the most.
Okay. So, why don't we go
back, listen to our dialogue
again, and we'll be
back with fluency builder.
Okay, Sally. We have
an artist here to help us.
We'll ask you questions
about the bank robber
you saw and Paul will draw a picture. Are
you ready? Yes. Well, he had brown hair,
long hair, and he had some facial hair. It
was brown too. Good. Okay, the facial hair,
was it a beard or
a mustache? Both.
His mustache was very short
and thin, just on the top of his lip.
Uh-huh. Hmm. Like this?
Yes, that's the mustache,
but the beard isn't
right. I mean, it didn't
cover his whole face. I
think it was just on his chin.
A goatee. Was it like
Paul's? Uh, yes, that's it.
He had a goatee. Okay.
Now, what about sideburns?
Did he have sideburns? Um,
yes. They were long and thick,
like yours. All right. There.
Was this the man you saw?
Yes, that's him. Hmm.
It looks a lot like you.
Hmm. Why, yes, he
does. Paul, where were you
on Friday afternoon?
What? That's ridiculous.
It wasn't me. I
didn't do anything.
I was over there doing the thing
with the man's man. Who'd do?
All right. So today in
Fluency Builder, we are
not really talking about
phrases as much as we're
talking about adjectives.
So words you can use to
describe facial hair.
Okay. So when the girl was
describing facial hair,
for example, she said the
mustache was very
short and thin. Okay.
A short and thin mustache.
So you think about it, you can
have a very thick mustache.
That's the opposite.
That means very hairy, very
wide. A thin mustache is like a line.
Okay. Okay. So for example,
Charlie Chaplin, he had a short
mustache, but it wasn't thin.
It was a little bit thick.
That's right. It was kind
of wide. But you think
of, you know, when you
see someone who's drawing a
mustache on a sign at a
restaurant or in a newspaper,
that's usually very thin.
It's very silly looking.
Right. So those are
different adjectives to
describe, not only a
mustache. So basically, we can
use these to describe
any sort of hair.
For example, the hair on your
head because he's got short hair.
That's right. Or I
could say, I have
long hair, long hair. Or
Margaret, because you have
thick hair. Thick.
Yeah. So if you have an
abundance of hair that
you would say it's thick.
That's right. There's
a, you know, it's like if
you put your hand in
it, it's very, it feels like
there's a lot that's
very thick hair. Okay.
Some people have thin hair,
so they don't have a lot of hair.
Okay. Good. And well,
moving on to the parts
of the face, we described
it before us to wear
a mustache is where a
goat he is. But let's take
a closer look at that.
For example, a mustache
is on your upper lip.
Right. So just above your
lip, under your nose, that's
where a mustache goes.
So that's the upper
lip. But if we're talking
about a goaty, it's not
just on your upper lip.
It's also wear on your chin, your chin. So
that's the very bottom point of your face.
So you have your
chin, your upper lip.
And also when we talked
about, for example, the side burns,
we talked about the
job, but also it could be
part of the cheek. Right.
So every person has
two cheeks, one on the
left and one on the right.
And those are a very
big part of your face
on the sides of your nose.
Okay. So you have your
chin, you have your cheeks,
you have your upper lip.
I think that's pretty much the only places
where you can grow also on your neck.
Yes, some people have it on their
neck or on the back of, well, no, it's not.
Some people also have
it on their neck. Right.
Okay. Very good. So a
lot of different words to
describe facial hair. Why
don't we go back, listen
to the dialogue one last
time and we'll be back
to talk some more. Okay,
Sally, we have an artist
here to help us. We'll
ask you questions about
the bank robber you saw
and Paul will draw a picture.
Are you ready? Yes.
Well, he had brown hair,
long hair, and he
had some facial hair.
It was brown too. Good.
Okay. The facial hair was it
a beard or a mustache?
Both. His mustache was
very short and thin,
just on the top of his lip.
Uh-huh. Hmm. Like this?
Yes, that's the mustache.
But the beard isn't
right. I mean, it didn't
cover his whole face. I
think it was just on his chin.
A goatee? Was it like
Paul's? Uh, yes, that's it.
He had a goatee. Okay.
Now, what about cybers?
Did he have cybers?
Um, yes. They were long
and thick, like yours. All right. There.
Was this the man you saw? Yes, that's him.
It looks a lot like
you. Hmm. Why?
Yes, he does. Paul, where
were you on Friday afternoon?
What? That's
ridiculous. It wasn't me.
I didn't do anything. I was
over there doing the thing
the best man to do. All
right, so talking about
facial hair, Catherine,
do you like men in
that have facial hair? Yes.
Yeah, you like mustache's
beards, goatees. Um,
well, it really depends.
I really like sideburns,
but um, sometimes people
don't do them correctly,
so I don't like them.
But, um, I like beards.
Um, and yeah, goatee.
I like facial hair.
You like facial hair.
Well, what is it about facial
hair on men that you like?
Man, they men. I don't know.
There's something, you
know, kind of rough about it.
Rough. Yeah. Yeah. I
don't like the, uh, the very
manicured, very
carefully cut facial hair.
I kind of like it a little bit
more on the rough side.
Okay. Um, it's interesting
because, uh, it's
interesting to see also
facial hair on, um, uh,
or long facial hair,
like for example, uh, the
guys from ZZ top. Yeah.
You know, they have like
really long beards. I
wonder how long it takes to
grow something like
this. I'm sure we could find
out on the internet, but, uh,
yeah, no, they have competitions.
There's a world
mustache competition
for example, and they have
the world's longest mustache.
And so the man, you know,
they measure his mustache.
It's three or three or four meters
or something. Yeah, it's really long.
Yeah. So I think your,
your hair keeps growing.
It just depends on
when you decide to cut it.
I think it's also a very cultural
thing, right? Some cultures are, uh,
able to grow a lot of
facial hair and like to do it.
Uh, others really
don't. For example,
you don't really see many Asians, uh, with,
uh, facial hair, with gotees or mustaches.
I think you see more
gotees than you see full
beards, actually, but, uh,
yeah, definitely East Asia.
It's not as common. Although India,
you see a lot, a little bit more facial.
A lot of mustaches
there. Yeah. Yeah.
So this is an interesting
question. Tell us how, uh,
popular it is in your
country, or if you like
men with facial hair,
or if you're a guy,
do you like to have a beard mustache
or a gotee? So come to our website, www.
EnglishPod.com, and we'll
see everyone there. Bye guys.